Shit!
- Come on!
- Reb!
What the fuck?!
It was supposed to be Lou.
She took away the most
important person in my life
and now she knows what it feels like.
If you could get me one
of those mini cameras.
I could probably video
the whole thing for ya.
I miss being just Kath.
It was quieter. In here.
I think that you're starting
to experience empathy.
You should sue the
Corrections Department.
- I'm gonna help you put together a case. okay?
- Okay.
He's gone. Roo.
No. no. no. no!
Rita Connors. you're under arrest
for absconding from protective custody.
- Will. please. just trust me.
- Governor to you!
I fucking trusted you once with
everything and you played me.
You fucking snake. You
did it. You killed Reb.
It was Sheila. Shit!
Sheila's dead. I killed the
fucking bitch 'cause she murdered Reb.
So I am declaring myself Top Dog!
It's useless.
All I got is one lousy scrag fight.
some dry humping and a few saggy tits.
Are there any decent tits in here?
Hey?
Oh. are you thinking about your dad?
Yeah. and Reets.
I haven't heard nothing
since her arrest.
Hey. Big news. Allie's lawyer just
filed her suit against the prison.
- You're gonna be rich. girl.
- Yeah. great.
What am I gonna spend it on?
Monte Carlos?
None of that shit goes
down without Lou's say-so.
Lou's in the slot.
- She's Top Dog.
- Says Lou!
No-one voted her in.
If you don't like it. Zaina.
you can challenge her when she gets here.
Fuck that!
Why don't we have a vote?
Hm? Today.
Hey. girls!
Who wants a proper vote
for Top Dog. eh?
- Eh?
- Let's do it! Yeah!
Which one of you bitches is
gonna go up against Lou. eh?
Eh?!
I thought so.
I will.
Boomer!
Boomer! Boomer! Boomer!
Two murders? I've been
gone less than a month!
And that is on top of a serious assault
resulting in severe
disability to a prisoner.
A prisoner. I might add.
who  is suing the fucking prison!
- What?!
- What we have here
is a clear case of
systematic mismanagement.
What do you expect? You cut staff.
- increased hours. closed protection.
- Are you blaming me for your mess?
Every decision you have made has
added more stress to the system.
The system is broken. Mr. Jackson.
and it calls for even
more stringent measures
to bring everybody into line.
We will target drug users.
Every prisoner will now
undergo a mandatory test.
Who's gonna do that? We're
short-staffed as it is!
Punishing drug users is
not gonna solve the problem.
It's liberal attitudes like
that that got us into this mess!
So. it's got nothing to do
with you slashing the budget?
My record stands for itself!
I don't think so.
I don't have these problems
anywhere else. only at this prison!
Now. Kelly and Keane both
had drugs in their system
and I am the one copping it from
the minister and the press. not you!
Ann. we only have so
many isolation cells.
I don't want drug users
in isolation. Vera!
I want them visible.
They will be named and shamed.
- Oh. my God!
- "Governor. it's the gate house."
"The brawler's just arrived."
Yeah. copy that.
Go on and say it. I fucked up.
The police have closed
down the investigation
into your undercover handle.
Yeah. They're saying I made it
all up just so I could take off.
Do you believe them?
No. But why did you run?
I wanted to see my dad before he died.
- And did you?
- Yeah.
I sung him home.
- Miss Bennett.
- Rita. um.
I wanted to say I'm really
sorry about your dad.
Thanks. I appreciate that.
Okay. I'll let you get on with it.
You're looking at
some serious jail time.
Just tell me what I can do to help.
It's over. Mr. Jackson. I'm done.
- Judy. no. II can do this.
- Hey. I know.
It's my penance.
I would even wipe your
bum if you asked me to.
Gross! Jesus Christ!
If it ever gets to that
point. you have my permission
- to smother me with a pillow.
- I'd let Boomer do that!
Hey...
Look. I told you I don't blame you.
Actually.
I. erm.
I do have a secret agenda.
My lawyer thinks I might get
a stay of proceedings
on compassionate grounds
if I can prove I'm your
partner and primary carer.
- My partner?
- The judge might adjourn
while the claim is investigated.
He's coming in tomorrow.
Hey. I'm serious about wiping your bum.
if that's what it takes!
Ah. Jesus. Bryant.
you are seriously sick!
I don't know what came
over me. I must be hormonal.
- Are you pregnant?
- No.
I'm just saying. I don't
know why I stuck me hand up!
Hey. Booms. you're gonna
be a kick-ass Top Dog.
Ah. fuck!
Rita! Oh. my God!
Ah. it's so good to see
you! Let me look at you!
I can't believe you're here! Oh!
- Hey. Boomer.
- Hey.
That's your cell there.
Connors. You know the drill.
Yeah. thanks. Mr. Stewart.
What have you gone and done to yourself?
I slipped in the shower.
I'm sorry about your dad.
Yeah. that's shit. eh?
Hey. I'm Judy. I've
heard a lot about you.
Ah. guess what?
There's a vote for Top Dog.
Booms is going up against Lou Kelly.
Remember I told you about her?
Ah. yeah. but I'm happy
to step aside. like. if...
if you wanted it!
- Hey.
I still can't believe it.
I feel like I let Dad down. you know?
No bloody way.
All he talked about was
how proud he was
and how much he loved you.
HeyAre you wearing the teal?
Trial's coming up. Reckon
I better get used to it. eh?
What? You can't give up!
You gotta fight them bastards!
I'm done. Roo. Jones has won.
You gotta tell them the
truth about what happened.
What they did. Morelli was shot dead.
Yeah. because he tried to shoot you.
They kidnapped me.
I can't be bringing you into
an investigation of his death!
- Bullshit you can't.
- Two black chicks.
both crims. against the cops?
We both know how that's gonna end.
- Reet. you...
- Listen.
Dad's dying wish was
for me to protect you
and that's what I'm gonna do.
see you get free.
I can't jeopardise that. I won't.
I forgot to tell you.
Marie's back in General.
Ah. you're shitting me?
Seems like she doesn't
wanna hurt me any more.
Oh. Miss Miles...
Any news on my transfer request?
As if I haven't got enough to do.
Come on. I don't ask for much!
Ask Mr. Jackson.
I'm sure you can find
some way to persuade him.
You want a transfer?
We had an arrangement and
you go and murder someone.
My bad.
What did killing Bausch achieve?
Did it bring Reb back?
She killed the person I
love most in this world.
now you tell me you
wouldn't have done the same.
The governor's letting you
out of the slot sometime today.
- It could be too late.
- For what?
The women are having a Top Dog vote.
It's between you and Jenkins.
Boomer?!
As if the women are
gonna vote against me!
They're all scared shitless now.
Good. Because I need you
controlling the women.
We have to work together to
bring this prison back into line.
Are you still serious
about getting rid of Jackson
- and making me governor?
- I'd need a fabulous reason.
Is fucking a prisoner fabulous enough?
She demanded your resignation.
Oh. she'll take it to the board.
What did you say?
I refused!
Well. who told her?
As far as I know. the only people
that know are you and Marie.
Well. I didn't tell her. Ann's
a friend but you're a closer one.
Look. why would Marie say something now?
She's been sitting on this for months!
- I'll talk to her.
- What. Winter? No. bad idea.
- Then. Ann wins and I'll have to resign.
- No!
Deny everything.
It's your word against
hers. You just have to...
hold your nerve.
Lie.
- Yeah. Boomer!
- Come on. Boomer.
- We're with you. Boomer.
- Boomer!
Yes!
What the fuck?!
- Oy!
- Oy. that's enough! Everybody settle down!
Do you wanna go back to the slot. Kelly?
You're too late! Boomer's Top Dog!
She won the vote fair and square!
- Yeah. Boomer!
- Is that right?
Yes. it is!
Then. I vote my right to challenge.
Shit.
Fucking hell!
We'll settle this with shivs.
If Lou Kelly wants a shiv
fight. I'll bloody give her one.
I'm done being pushed around by her!
What's the point of even having a vote?
There's two ways to become Top Dog:
either win the vote or win the fight.
If Lou Kelly wants it
so bad. let her have it.
Nah. I can't let the slag
who put Allie in thatthing
just. like. walk all
over us! Nah. she's toast!
Boomer. don't do this for me!
- You don't have to fight her. Booms.
- Yes. I do!
I have to.
- Rita.
- Marie.
Long time no see.
Not long enough.
Just so we're clear.
Ruby's got nothing to worry about.
Winter. I've got news
on your transfer request.
It's been denied.
By order of Mr. Jackson.
I keep thinking about Reb's funeral.
His bitch of a mother would've
put him a dress. buried him as a...
I wasn't there for him.
I didn't get to bury Danny. either.
This fucking place!
- Taking on Boomer's not a good idea.
- Ah. she's a big fucking baby.
No. it's not her you gotta worry about.
It's Connors. It's Ruby's sister.
- She's back and she's no fucking slouch.
- Rita! You're back!
She killed my 2-I-C Drago
with her bare hands.
Oh. no. I'm fine!
And she's loyal. too. so
she won't just stand by
and watch you stick a shiv up Boomer.
- Attention. compound. Attention. compound.
- Thanks for the heads-up.
All H Block prisoners assemble at
the medical unit for a drug test.
Fuck! Fuck me! I need
some clean fucking piss.
Repeat. All H Block prisoners assemble
- at the medical unit for a drug test.
- That can be arranged.
Kill two birds with one stone.
Okay. I'll inform all the
relevant parties. Thank you.
Clean-up of the seedling
yard's almost finished.
Great. Hey. come in. I want a word.
If it's about Will and a
prisoner. I already know.
That they're having an
inappropriate relationship.
About the ridiculous accusation!
Did Winter tell you this?
Well. I would tell you. but remember
that protocol you schooled me in
about protecting prison informants?
She's a liar.
And a manipulator. The
board will never believe her
and it will backfire on you.
We'll see. They're sending
someone over tomorrow.
Hey. good luck with the market
garden. Let me know it goes.
It's a great initiative. Well done.
You know. it'd take the
heat off all of us if
Will just fell on his sword.
Like Winter allegedly did.
I thought you might
be interested to know.
Winter's been requesting
a transfer out of H-6.
but Will's refused.
Is that right?
I tried to help someone.
Help them how?
Give them information.
To. uh. to solve a problem.
- And how did it go?
- Not good. I was rejected.
How did that make you feel?
Hurt.
- Why do you think that...
- I was hurt.
No. that you were rejected?
I might've done something to. um...
to injure that person in the past.
And how do you feel about that?
I feel...
regret.
Possibly...
guilt?
Interesting.
That's an empathetic reaction. Joan.
That suggests that our therapy
and the Psuldrycin might
actually be working.
"Attention. compound. Count
will commence in ten minutes."
What the hell is she
turning this place into?
- Seriously. restraint stations?
- Will.
they're being trialled
in all Victoria prisons.
Yes. Which Ann happens to oversee.
They are designed for limited
use. They are highly regulated.
There is a two-hour limit.
- Wait. you're defending this torture device?
- Of course I'm not.
I just want you to concentrate
on one battle at a time.
Right now. you need to
focus on your career.
There's a member of the board
coming tomorrow. Helen Stanfield.
Good. I can take this
bullshit up with her.
Yeah. I don't think
that's a good idea!
Can you focus on one problem
at a time?
You can't help the women
if you don't have a job!
Remember what I told you.
Deny. deny. deny.
Why do you wanna
transfer out of this unit?
I'd hate to be in here without you.
Guilt.
Guilt?
About what?
I created a monster. Kath.
who ended up hurting someone
that I care about very much.
But in the end...
in the end...
I had no choice...
What's up?
Huh?
Nothing.
Boomer...
I'm scared.
I'm not scared of Lou.
right? I'm not scared of her.
She's just a big. angry
bully. you know. just...
Ah. man.
I just wish everything
was different. I wish...
I wish I was having a baby.
I wish she was back to normal.
I wish you was going out on your parole.
And I wouldn't even be crying over you!
But. um. most of all.
I wish that Lou wouldn't
cut me beautiful face
'cause then I'd never get a Roo!
Hey.
We're all gonna be there.
- I'll be your second.
- Me what?
It means if you chicken
out. I'll take your place.
I'll be your third.
Just in case Ruby caves.
Oh. I guess that makes me your fourth.
Ahh!
Yous would all be fucking useless!
Attention. compound.
H Block are now called for breakfast.
Hey. bitch! What up!
Yeah. let's work out. hey?
Why aren't you at breakfast?
Not much of an appetite.
I prefer the jacket.
Reckon that belonged to someone else!
I don't think I know
that person any more.
Ruby...
She's had a long time to come to
terms with Dad dying. but for me...
Ten years I was someone else.
Lost touch with my
core. you know. my roots.
Going back home. it...
it made me doubt who I am.
I lost touch with who I was for a time.
It can be hard to come back from that.
Maybe even impossible.
You're a good fella. Mr. Jackson.
Maybe I will go and have some breakfast.
I don't wanna be fading away now. do I?
Has anyone seen Rita since the count?
Has she gone to breakfast?
Hey.
- How you feeling?
- Mm.
Booms. I've been thinking about Lou.
I reckon I've got a plan.
- I hope it's nothing stupid.
- Nah. it's nothing stupid!
Just go to brekkie and
I'll sort it out. Go!
- I'll see you later.
- Yeah.
- What the fuck are these?
- Smiles said they're called restraint stations.
They're for locking us up.
- More Reynolds bullshit.
- Yeah! Nazi fucking pricks.
Fucking stocks is what they are.
Check out the trackie!
Does wonders for the figure.
- Hey. I'll get the door for you.
- Ah. no! I can get it. It's all right.
That Judy. she likes to
make a fuss of Allie. eh?
Ah. yeah! She's a big suck.
- Me and Rubes don't get a look-in.
- Where is Roo?
- Um...
- Boomer?
Where's Ruby?
Dunno.
Um. she said she had a plan to
help me with the Lou situation.
- What kind of plan?
- I dunno. She didn't say.
She said it's nothing stupid!
Enjoy your last meal.
What the fuck are you doing?
Committing murder? Get out of here!
I wasn't gonna kill her.
I was just gonna shiv her
- a couple of times.
- You what?!
Put her in medical for a day.
Make her miss the showdown.
You'd risk an assault charge
this close to your parole?
- I'm doing it for Boomer.
- Boomer can fight her own battles.
- No. she can't 'cause she's scared.
- Well...
What if this Lou just
challenges her again next week?
- Then I'll shiv her again next week.
- What's got into you. Roo?
- What's gotten into me?
- Yeah.
I'll do whatever it takes to protect
my best mate. Rita. that's what.
I haven't given up.
I've got Winter.
Sit down.
You'll be required to attend
an enquiry this afternoon.
An enquiry into what?
Allegations that you had an
inappropriate relationship
with a senior male member of staff.
I want you to know. I understand
that you are the real victim in this.
It's such an abuse of
power and male privilege.
It must've been awful for you.
- I've got no idea...
- I know how difficult it's been
for you to remain at
this prison. given...
everything.
If you tell the truth at this enquiry.
I'll personally
guarantee you a transfer.
And not just out of H Block.
An interstate transfer
to a minimum security prison farm
where nobody knows you
or has history with you.
Where you can have a fresh start.
- There you go.
- Great.
What are the results of the drug tests?
The GM wants them put
on the new restraints.
That's not what I...
What are we looking at?
Mostly methamphetamines and MDMA.
It looks like our LSD days are over.
Although we did get
one anomalous result.
I've sent it off for further analysis.
- Anomalous how?
- It's not a drug we test for.
- What prisoner?
- Ferguson.
It's as if there are...
two halves.
I realise how prosaic that sounds.
I'm not confused. They're not
distinct personalities. I am Joan.
I know I'm Joan.
It's just...
there's this part of me.
the Kath part.
where there's a genuine desire...
for human connection.
and it's constantly at
odds with my thoughts.
Fantasies.
Urges.
Well. that's the nature
of human emotion. I mean.
they're quite often in conflict.
I'm finding it difficult
to negotiate the boundaries.
In the past.
how did you...
exercise these urges?
I took pride in exploiting
the weakness in others.
You could say I created monsters
and I used them to hurt others.
You turned off the nanny cam.
Um. yeah. 'cause I didn't
really like the idea
of you spying on me all the time.
Sorry for being concerned.
There's just no point in both
of us staying up half the night.
Yeah. I agree. So let me have a turn.
I read on this website that
- playing white noise can help.
- Oh. for God's sake. Jake!
I'm only making the suggestion to help
and you won't accept my
help because of your pride!
It has nothing to do with pride!
So. you don't trust me with her?
Is that what you're saying? I
thought we got past all of this.
Do you know arrogant that is? We
don't just get past all of this.
Right. so withholding
Grace is just to punish me?
Ah. fuck!
And these others that
you heard. they were
people that you disliked?
Who disappointed me the most.
So you cared about them.
In as much as I could care about anyone.
These impulses. Joan...
you control them.
It's like the parable of the Two Wolves.
We all have a good wolf and a bad wolf
fighting each other inside of us.
The winner
is whichever wolf we choose to feed.
Time's up for today.
I won't let you wipe yourself out!
If you want. I can always
take this to a lawyer
- and sue for joint custody!
- A lawyer?!
Did you seriously just
threaten me with a lawyer?
- Only because you're too stubborn to accept my help!
- Get out of my office!
I will never let you
take Grace away from me!
Keep moving. Ferguson.
Miss Miles. what's going on?
I told you. I'm not on the gear.
That's not what your piss says. Connors.
Then. you fucked up!
Check my piss again!
If you think you're putting me on
that thing. you can think again!
You shouldn't have
taken the drugs. then!
- I fucking didn't!
- Hold her down!
Well. the piss swap worked.
Yeah.
Novak and Bryant have just been
taken to see Bryant's lawyer.
Tell everyone the fight's happening now.
Boomer!
- Boom!
- I'm on the bog!
Lou's called the fight forward.
What?
- Sshe can't fucking do that.
- She paid off a screw.
She says it's now or never.
Now? But Allie's not even here.
- Well. Allie can't fight for ya!
- Yeah. no. I know that!
- I'm just saying I don't have any crew.
- Whoo!
- I wanna be in Boomer's crew!
- Yeah. you do.
- I'll be there.
- Come on. shit's going down!
- Everyone's going down there now.
- Come on. you slapper. come down!
Come on!
Booms?
I'm just...
taking a dump. all right?
Tell 'em I'm...
Tell 'em I'll be there
when I'm finished.
Come on.
Where the fuck's Boomer?
- I didn't bet on this horse!
- Where's the big lug?
She's too piss-weak to show up.
Taking care of business.
- Come on!
- What?
She'll be here.
- Well. if she doesn't show. she forfeits.
- I said she'll be here!
Fuck!
- Fuck.
- You did tell her?
Yeah. I told her.
Fuck it. I'll go and get her.
Once you're in. no-one gets
out. Not until it's done.
- That's the rules.
- Bow-bow.
No! Ohh!
I can't do this! I can't do it!
I can't do it! I can't do this!
I can't do this!
- That's it. folks.
- Where the fuck is she?
- She's a no-show.
- She's coming. she is!
I'm her second.
Her what?
I'll fight.
- Go on. Ruby!
- Yeah!
Now. are you sure about that.
you little pocket-rocket. hm?
You wanna dyke-off for Top Dog?
You give us a bad name.
- You're late.
- You're the one who moved the fight forward.
I'm fucking early!
Thanks. Rubes. I got this.
Okay. Suzy Booms...
- let's go.
- Let's go!
Come on!
You'll love this! Show her!
Go. Boomer!
Punch her! Yes!
- You've got this!
- Come on. take her down!
Shit!
Stronger. Boom!
- This is it. Booms. You got this. Come on.
- How is this a fair fight?
Oi!
Come on!
No. no. no. no. no!
What are you doing. Boomer?
- Come on!
- All right.
Protect your face! Line up!
- That's it. Boomer! Come on!
- Fucking get her!
Get her!
Ahh!
Give it up. Suze.
Fucking finish it!
Give it up or I will
cut your fucking throat!
Boomer!
You win.
Yeah-eah!
Good fight. Booms.
Ladies!
Shit! Shit. Booms. Shit!
Hey...
Get in here. Get on your
radio and call Medical.
This is Sierra 10. I need
immediate medical assistance
- in the laundry.
- It was a good fight.
It was. wasn't it?
- Yeah. you did a good job!
- Medical assistance required in the laundry.
Immediate medical assistance
required in the laundry.
And how would you describe your
relationship with Miss Bryant?
She's my partner.
Romantic partner?
Mm-hm.
And. uh.
would you say you depend on her.
due to your condition?
II couldn't cope without her.
Especially in here.
Well. as soon as you get
that impact statement done.
I'll start the ball rolling
on a motion to adjourn.
Ok. Tell Miss Stanfield I'll
be there in just a minute.
Thank you.
Jenkins is off to hospital
with half a dozen stab wounds.
Tell me you're not responsible.
You wanted me as Top Dog.
What I want is for us to work together!
And here I am...
again.
Look. I will make this worth your while.
but I need a compliant
and placid prison body.
Mm. Well. sometimes it just takes
a little bit of blood to be spilt.
When you and your mates
closed the protection unit.
you knew there'd be casualties.
Short-term pain for long-term gain.
Thank you. Kelly. I do not need
you to boil down my business plan.
Sheila should've been in protection.
You let a mass-murderer in a general.
Oh...
So. you're blaming me for
your girlfriend's death now?
Officer!
Fuck off! Fuck you!
What the fuck are you looking at?
Thank you. Mr. Jackson.
You can step out.
Mr. Jackson has comprehensively denied
any form of inappropriate
relationship with you.
I assure you.
everything you tell me will
be completely confidential.
So. how would you characterise
your relationship with the governor?
Well. the governor-Top Dog
relationship's a well-established one.
so we work closely together.
We were close. yeah.
You had private meetings?
Yes. Look. occasionally I had to
divulge some sensitive information.
for the good of the women. of course.
and for that reason. they
had to be private. yeah.
Miss Winter.
did your relationship
ever become sexual?
No. of course not!
Mr. Jackson was totally professional.
Why did you lie?
You were always good to me.
Christ. you saved my life. Will.
I mean. Mr. Jackson.
- I'm not gonna thank you. not after...
- No. it's okay.
I wouldn't expect you to.
I don't deserve it.
So. what do I write?
Just. I don't know. write down
what you said to the lawyer.
It was some pretty good spin.
It wasn't spin. I meant it.
Hey. look who's here.
Reet. You right?
Can you believe those
restraint stations?
- Fucking fascists!
- Yeah. Whitefellas love their chains.
Hey. any news on Boomer?
Jenkins's natural padding
protected her vital organs.
Just a few flesh wounds.
She'll be back tomorrow.
I feel terrible we weren't there.
Hey. it wasn't our fault.
You're right. Roo.
Fuck the teal.
Let's fight them bastards.
Come 'ere!
Do you still wanna transfer out?
You can't hide from yourself. Kath.
For what it's worth...
I don't think you had a choice.
Sometimes you have to kill
the monsters you've created.
I miss him!
Yeah.
Me. too.
Ssh...
But it's all over now. sweetheart.
Yeah. you're Top Dog...
Sheila's dead.
There's nothing else to fight for.
Sheila didn't kill Reb.
This whole fucking place killed Reb.
Reynolds. Miller.
Jackson. Bennett.
It won't be over till I've
killed every one of them...
and this prison is ripped the fuck apart.